## Hey 👋 I'm Alexander Smagin

me@dotzero.ru github.com/dotzero linkedin.com/in/dotzero

I'm backend engineer from Moscow



I have solid experience in designing distributed microservices architecture from scratch. Migrating huge existing applications to microservices and making them scalable and reliable.

I'm hiring new talents and leading business initiatives if it's needed to get things done.

#### Tech stack



## Experience

## **Lead Backend Developer @ Avito** — Moscow, Russia March 2017 — Present



Avito is the leading classified ads service in Russia, with nearly 50 million monthly users and more than 80 million active advertisements posted on its platform.

- I'm leading the architecture of high load services developed in monetization cluster
- Building a lot of microservices using Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis and Apache Kafka
- Managing infrastructure as code in Kubernetes, Helm, etc. I'm familiar with the principles of SRE
- Working out development approaches to minimize Time To Market
- Maintain a high engineering culture by promoting modern development technologies and reducing technical debt
- Leading the information security role in my team
- Participate in hiring new talents and improving the hiring process in the company

# **Senior Backend Developer @ Habr** — Moscow, Russia September 2015 — March 2017



Habr (*since 2018; formerly Habrahabr*) is Europe's largest collaborative user-generated content platform about IT, computer science and anything related to the Internet, owned by TechMedia.

- Developed new product features like Markdown and LaTeX support and internal analytics system
- Supported a lot of services using PHP, Go, MySQL и Sphinx Search
- Participated in the merging of TechMedia products (<u>megamozg.ru</u> and <u>geektimes.ru</u> into <u>habr.com</u>)
- Hiring new talents

# **Senior Backend Developer @ Webit** — Moscow, Russia July 2009 — August 2015



Building new and supporting existing online shopping platforms for enterprise customers.

- Developed new and supporting exists online shopping platforms
- I have solid experience
- Experienced with dozen famous frameworks, cms and other customers solutions
- Leaded DevOps role, and bootstrapped CI/CD pipeline
- Maintain a high engineering culture by promoting modern development technologies and reducing technical debt
- Participate in hiring new talents and improving the hiring process in the company

### Certification

#### Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP / PEN-200)

Offensive Security Certified Professional is an ethical hacking certification offered by Offensive Security that teaches penetration testing methodologies and the use of the tools included with the Kali Linux distribution

#### **Analytics Based Product Management Course**

GoPractice, Inc

### Education

#### Rosnou — Russian New University

Information systems and technologies

#### Math college MEPHI

Graphic design

#### Personal info

#### Hobbies:

My main hobbies are traveling, photography, and flying drones.

#### Languages:

English — B1

Russian — Native

#### Pet projects:

https://github.com/dotzero

https://dotzero.blog